<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: whois | Usha Guduri]]></title>
  <link href="http://ushaguduri.com/blog/categories/whois/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ushaguduri.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-19T22:31:56-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://ushaguduri.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Usha Guduri]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Domain Registration Vs. Web Hosting]]></title>
    <link href="http://ushaguduri.com/blog/2012/10/01/domain-registration-vs-web-hosting/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-01T14:22:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ushaguduri.com/blog/2012/10/01/domain-registration-vs-web-hosting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Any substantial group/idea/person has to have a website these days to prove their legitimacy even in the cyberspace.</p>

<p>Now where does that start? With signing up for a easy to recognize name that is associated with the entity at a Domain Registrar - one who makes sure that you own that name and no one else can get that name, like GoDaddy, 1and1, Network Solutions etc. And you pay for their services-anywhere from $10 to $100+ a year. (Prepare to shell out in the thousands if you want a name real bad, that is already taken). At this point, you only have the name to your credit, with a generic message showing at most but no where close to what you want it to actually be like, when you visit the site via a web browser.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The next step is to get some space on a machine connected to the internet-always, so that John in Bangkok or Joe in Paris can see your website anytime of the day. Called Web Hosting, there are so many choices again here - shared, dedicated, colocation - including the big names like Amazon Web Services, Google App Engine, Microsoft Azure etc.</p>

<p>For a simple website, I suggest something like HostGator (best of the lot if you ask me), BlueHost, 1and1, Namecheap and such, where you can get both the above mentioned services in 1 spot with an easy-to-use Control Panel to manage everything.</p>

<p>By the way, for the geek in you,
<code>
whois example.com
</code>
shows the information you used to sign up with the Domain Registrar and</p>

<p><code>
nslookup example.com
dig example.com
ping example.com
</code>
show which IP address(machine) the domain is being served from.</p>

<p>Oh and the next time, I can point anyone, who still ponders why pay twice and are they over-charging etc, straight here..hehe</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
