<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: sql | Usha Guduri]]></title>
  <link href="http://ushaguduri.com/blog/categories/sql/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ushaguduri.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-06T13:21:08-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://ushaguduri.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Usha Guduri]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MYSQL Effects on Views from Changes to Table Structure]]></title>
    <link href="http://ushaguduri.com/blog/2012/03/12/mysql-effects-on-views-from-changes-to-table-structure/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-12T15:23:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://ushaguduri.com/blog/2012/03/12/mysql-effects-on-views-from-changes-to-table-structure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Au contraire, there are <strong>no</strong> effects of changing a table’s structure on a dependent view in MySQL! I’ve heard that other databases like Oracle automatically pick up changes on the table’s structure, but in MySQL the view is frozen upon creation.
<code>sql
CREATE VIEW my_view AS SELECT * from my_table;
ALTER TABLE my_table ADD COLUMN my_new_column &lt;data and constraints&gt;;
</code></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>If you expect to do
<code>sql
SELECT my_new_column FROM my_view;
</code>
it sure is going to fail.</p>

<p><strong>Solution:</strong> Either drop the view and recreate it:
<code>sql
DROP VIEW my_view;
CREATE VIEW my_view AS SELECT * from my_table;
</code>
or alter the view:
<code>sql
ALTER VIEW my_view (&lt;list of all columns&gt;) SELECT * FROM my_table;
</code>
<strong>Lesson:</strong> Do not forget about the dependent views when you change a table’s structure!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Database Migrations: Continue on Expected Errors]]></title>
    <link href="http://ushaguduri.com/blog/2012/03/10/database-migrations-continue-on-expected-errors/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-10T15:07:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://ushaguduri.com/blog/2012/03/10/database-migrations-continue-on-expected-errors</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ever ran into a situation where the migrations would work just as expected in production, but for some reason, are not applicable to other environments? Could be either because the tables exist in production, but for saving space, the other environments use views on it or because you had to manually add the column to set up the new data, so that the application would not come crashing down.</p>

<p>Your approach would really depend on how the migrations are set up. A simple solution no matter what(if you are using straight SQL), is to surround the actual migration sql in a stored procedure and set up continue handlers only for errors that you are already expecting like so:</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>```sql
DELIMITER //
CREATE PROCEDURE AddColumnIfNecessary ()
BEGIN</p>

<pre><code>DECLARE continue handler for 1060 BEGIN END;
ALTER TABLE mytable add newcolumn &lt;type and constraints&gt;;
</code></pre>

<p>END //
DELIMITER ;
CALL AddColumnIfNecessary();
DROP AddColumnIfNecessary;
```</p>

<p>If you are gearing up for table not existing too, then add another handler for 1146 as:
```sql</p>

<pre><code>DECLARE continue handler for 1146 BEGIN END;
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>If you are working with views by the same name, you’d see “is not BASE TABLE”(error 1347), not table does not exist. So you’d need:
```sql</p>

<pre><code>DECLARE continue handler for 1347 BEGIN END;
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>Essentially, its like try - catch for SQL! The above handlers, if you noticed, are not really doing anything between the BEGIN and END. But you can set up any additional SQL in there. However, make sure to declare the handlers before you actually execute the SQL which is going to “throw” these errors</p>

<p><strong>Lesson:</strong> Although there are work-arounds like the above, think through why the purpose of “migrations” is defeated in the first place and if the process(whatever triggered the need for altering the table) should even be part of a migration when you are manually meddling with the database.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
